<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Retro&#39;s Space</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Retro&#39;s Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 14:24:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Macbook Air</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/macbook-air/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/macbook-air/</guid>
      <description>A previous post talked about my then recently purchased Thinkpad X200, and whilst I love that machine and still continue to use it, it definitely has its problems. For example the battery life was just not up to par with my lifestyle. Especially how it has transformed with University. The Thinkpad just isn&amp;rsquo;t able to keep up with a 7-8 hour day without needing multiple charges, which would be extremely limiting.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;A previous post talked about my then recently purchased Thinkpad X200, and
whilst I love that machine and still continue to use it, it definitely has its
problems. For example the battery life was just not up to par with my lifestyle.
Especially how it has transformed with University. The Thinkpad just isn&amp;rsquo;t able
to keep up with a 7-8 hour day without needing multiple charges, which would be
extremely limiting.
For this reason and others as well, I decided that I needed a new laptop. Now, my
budget was very good, on the order of a couple thousand pounds, therefore I was not
limited in my choice set. I had a few simple requirements that helped narrow down
the options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can not run Windows or ChromeOS. I have not ran windows in some years now and
I am not willing to start again here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to have at least 8 hours of continual use in it without charging. It
is not a good quality of mine that I often forget to charge my devices but I
could make the choice to make my life easier with a better battery life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It had to be powerful. One of the downsides to the Thinkpad is the speed, not
being able to comfortably run a browser in a graphical environment would make
University a much worse experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be cool. There&amp;rsquo;s no worse laptop for University in my opinion than a
&amp;ldquo;gaming laptop&amp;rdquo;. The flashy RGB lights, the weird pointy shape and the absolute
size of some of the laptops that I see just turn me off. Laptops, especially work
laptops, are meant to be light and portable. Why would I carry a gaming pc cosplayed
as a laptop around my University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must last long. I am not okay with the idea of replacing my laptop every year.
The laptop must reasonably last until the end of University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, I only really faced two options, either a framework laptop loaded
with Linux, or a Macbook. What made me decide was the power and the battery, due to
linux on laptops not being all the way there yet, the power efficiency of the Macbook
became one of the key selling points for me. Also the price to power of the
Macbook made much more sense to me. After lots (and I mean lots) of mulling this
decision over, I eventually decided to get a 13&amp;quot; M3 Macbook Air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unluckily for me, I got it just a few months before the 16Gb RAM base model upgrade,
meaning that I paid extra to get 16Gb of RAM. Aside from that I got the 512Gb SSD
storage, which has been more than plenty. Along with the 10 core GPU, I was set.
Now I could have gotten the M2 for considerably cheaper, however due to this machine
both needing to last a few years and being my main machine for any University programming,
I decided to go for the M3.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What The Fuck Is Wrong With The Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-the-fuck-is-wrong-with-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-the-fuck-is-wrong-with-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>aaa
Advertisements aaaa
AI aaaa
Shortform content </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;aaa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;advertisements&#34;&gt;Advertisements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aaaa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ai&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aaaa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;shortform-content&#34;&gt;Shortform content&lt;/h1&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinkpad X200</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/thinkpad-x200/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 12:59:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/thinkpad-x200/</guid>
      <description>My Lenovo Thinkpad X200 is, in my opinion at least, one of the best laptops out there. Unless you really need the extra oomph in performance, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t pay sky high prices for these top of the line laptops out there. I got my Thinkpad off of ebay for £209.99, the base price was £179.99 but I shilled out an extra £30 for a RAM and an SSD upgrade (4Gb &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; 8Gb, 128Gb &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; 256Gb).</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;My Lenovo Thinkpad X200 is, in my opinion at least, one of the best laptops out there. Unless you
really need the extra oomph in performance, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t pay sky high prices for these top of the
line laptops out there. I got my Thinkpad off of ebay for £209.99, the base price was £179.99 but I
shilled out an extra £30 for a RAM and an SSD upgrade (4Gb &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; 8Gb, 128Gb &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; 256Gb). Another thing
I should mention is that it did come pre-librebooted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-battery&#34;&gt;The battery&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll just give it to you straight, the battery life on my Thinkpad X200 is shit. Even with minimal
usage, I still run through multiple charges a day. For many people, including me, this is an issue.
Luckily in most of my lessons at college I have access to a socket that I can charge from whilst
working, this is a different case during independent study however, most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m having to
keep a watchful eye on my battery life as to not run out of charge without having saved all my work.
However, this is not a deal breaker for me. The Thinkpad X200 has a removable battery which means
eventually I will invest in a spare battery for these situations where I cannot charge for a large
period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;performance&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I set my expectations low but honestly the performance from the X200 has been largely perfect.
It does everything I need it to do, and even more. We were even able to get
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tetr.io&#34;&gt;Tetrio&lt;/a&gt; working with not much lag/jank. If you wanted a beefy gaming laptop
to play games on the go, this is certainly not it, but if you just need a cheap-ish laptop to do
work on, this is where I would point you.
Personally, I do my college work on this laptop. Such work includes essay writing for my Psychology
class, Programming and notes for computer science, not so legally obtained textbooks for maths, and
just general miscellaneous work I have to do such as writing my personal statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-comments&#34;&gt;Other Comments&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not be for everyone but I absolutely love the rugged aesthetics of it. The keyboard that
actually bounces back and feels like an actual keyboard, the trackpoint sitting there with no
trackpad in sight, random lights and buttons all with their own purpose. To me it&amp;rsquo;s just pretty.
I love just throwing it into my backpack without a case and knowing that it&amp;rsquo;ll be alright, and that if
it&amp;rsquo;s not alright, its not that hard to fix (comparative to other brands).
I&amp;rsquo;m no utilitarian but this just makes me appreciate its sheer functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
